Lola Santos

Former Design Lead, Current Conservation Student

coyotedagger@gmail.com www.lolasantos.xyz

Summary

Product designer with 10+ years of experience making a career change into conservation. Currently enrolled full-time in Merritt College's Natural History and Sustainability program. Experience with managing small teams, GIS, Python, developing project strategy, mentoring, and data management, as well as bird and plant identification and trail restoration. Excited to use passion for Californian ecology and experience with mapping software to help protect these unique ecosystems.

Experience

2019 - 2024 Unity Technologies

□ Design Lead, Multiplayer

- Defined 2-year design strategy for creating a suite of multiplayer game development tools.
- Designed 5 high-impact tools in the Unity editor, from wireframes to launch, using Figma.
- Led 3 designers to unify 10 conflicting legacy tools as part of unification initiative.
- Mentored a junior designer and successfully guided her through a promotion.

→ Senior Designer, Labs

- Designed an experimental in-editor tool to generate game scenes on the fly.
- Designed and patented a tool to build and manage game economies.

2017 – 2019 **Senior UX Engineer**, Mapbox

• Designed and developed AR prototypes for geospatial needs using Unity, C#, and Swift.

2016 – 2017 **Product Designer**, thoughtbot

• Worked with 15+ clients to prototype, design, and test their websites and apps.

2015 – 2016 **Product Designer**, CoMedia Design

• Designed websites and assets, like icon sets, for clients.

2014 - 2015 Freelance Designer

• Designed websites for small Bay Area businesses.

2013 – 2014 **Software Engineer**, Goodreads

• Coded user-facing features on the Goodreads website using Ruby and JavaScript.

Education

2024 - current Merritt College Conservation and Resource Management certificate

2009 – 2013 University of California, Berkeley Computer Science B.A., French Literature minor

Volunteering & Personal Projects

Volunteer, Claremont Canyon Conservancy

• Clearing invasive plants and improving drainage along trails.

Volunteer, The Crucible

• Welcoming guests, cleaning studio spaces, setting up for special events.

Writer, Cowgirl

• Maintaining personal newsletter about the history and ecology of the American West.

Skills

- Trail maintenance, habitat restoration, science writing, bird and plant identification
- GIS, Python, Ruby, C#, UX/UI design, tech writing, user research, digital illustration